# MAXIMILIANO HERNANDEZ CASTILLO

Software Engineer | Front-End Developer | Back-End Developer



## **EMAIL**

MAXHERNANDEZCASTILLO@GMAIL.COM

## **WEBSITE**

https://maxkalavera.github.io/

## **SKILLS**

Problem analysis / solving (Algorithms)

Linux based systems

MacOS

Python

Javascript

NodeJs

PostgreSQL

**SOLite** 

Redis

Django

Celery

ReactJS

Webpack

RollUp

HTML5 CSS

SASS

Redux Jenkins

Inkscape

Gimp

Figma

Git Docker

Docke Bash

sh

English Spanish

## **PROFILE**

Software engineer born in Monterrey, Mexico, with 3 years of professional experience building web applications. Proficient in Python and Javascript; Skilled translating business requirement into software solutions; Extensive experience with Linux systems, being an active user; Essential knowledge in graphic design focused in the design of software graphical interfaces.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Software Engineering**

AUGUST 2009 - JANUARY 2015

Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León - San Nicolás de los Garza, Nuevo León Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering (Ingeniería en Tecnología de Software)

Projects highlights

# **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

## **Machine Learning**

Coursera

Dec 2020

Credential ID: A8FCSDG5P9M9

See credential

# **Graphic Design Specialization**

Coursera

Aug 2021

Credential ID: K6495WPA96GR

See credential

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Full Stack Software Engineer**

Crea Libre / Evient, San Nicolas, Nuevo León

June 2017 - June 2019, 2 years

Contributed largely in the implementation of a Web application by heavily participating in the planning of the application's architecture and working on implementing client's requested features.

- Developing new Web features for Front-end / Back-end.
- Building a developing environment for a team to develop and actively provide feedback and test new features using Jenkins, Python and ReactJS tools.
- Involved in planning and decision making for implementing new features.

# Software Engineer / Front-End Developer

Wizeline, Guadalajara, Jalisco

January 2022 - July 2022, 7 months

Developing Web interfaces using primarily ReactJS framework.

- Developing front-end interfaces using ReactJS together with NodeJS developing tools.
- Involved in designing new features using Figma tool.
- Involved in Python async task tool maintenance.